Wenxin Ye

San Francisco, CA 94132 • 415-888-1130 • whenxin.ye@gmail.com • Linkedin.com/in/wenxin-ye/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Marketing professional with 2 years' working experience in SEO, SEM, social media, content, e-mail, and influencer marketing. Met 130% of user acquisition goal through managing multi-channels. Improved 25% customer service efficiency by systemizing the communication process. A team player with people management skills and entrepreneurial spirit. Looking to leverage proven leadership and marketing skills for a fast-growing company as digital marketing specialist.

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

BOOSTINSIDER INC, an influencer marketing agency and software company. October 2017 – Present **Digital Marketing Specialist**

Plan and execute influencer marketing campaigns for global clients. Strategize both paid and organic social media marketing channels with the goal of user acquisition. Manage a content team of 2. Served as the point of contact for PR and partnership companies. Manage 40% of company client accounts.

Key Accomplishments:

- Saved more than 60% of cost for clients' influencer marketing campaigns by negotiating terms with influencers.
- Ranked image from no presence to No.1. by performing SEO through establishing editorial calendar and building backlinks.
- Increased 50% web traffic and 20% user signups by strategizing and optimizing paid search campaigns including Google Adwords and Quora Ads. Report to C-level execs on weekly-basis.
- Cumulatively generated 200+ shares and 60k+ article views in 2 months and increased 10% of total user signups by developing and executing blog content strategies.

TOLOCAL, INC, a Facebook lead generation company. September 2017 – October 2017 **Paid Display Specialist**

Contributing to the growth of the business by generating and converting Facebook leads to sales.

Key Accomplishments:

- Hit the ROI benchmark in just 1 month (usually 2 month) by performing A/B testing, tracking and optimizing Facebook campaign performance on a daily basis.
- Converted 10% of leads to sales by using Mailchimp to execute email campaigns.

GOPACKUP, INC, an online travel marketplace. May 2017 – August 2017 **Social Media Marketing Intern**

Optimized social media campaigns by analyzing user behavior data on Google Analytics. Conducted keyword research to identified customer trends. Supported business development by coordinating tasks among design and technical teams.

Key Accomplishments:

- Increased web traffic by 50% by planning and executing creative marketing campaign as well as developing campaign timeline and collaborating with cross-functional teams.
- Sourced social media influencers to further campaigns by using Followerwonk and Netlytic.
- Optimized functions of apps and websites for outside agents by collaborating with cross-functional teams.

COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP

ZAIGEZAIGU GALA.ORG, a volunteer community hosted by high-tech company employees. CA, Nov 2018 – Present **Marketing Manager**

Built brand online presence from ground up. Recruit and manage a team of 15 and oversee all aspect of online and offline marketing activities. Working closely with event production team, setting clear P0, P1 deadlines and success hurdles.

EDUCATION

Gary J. Sbona Business Honors | **Bachelor of Arts in Marketing** | San Jose State University, 2017 GPA 3.48

<u>Coursework</u>: Marketing Research, Quant Bus Analysis

<u>Certificates, Tools & Skillsets</u>: Google Ads Search Certification, Hootsuite Platform Certification; Advanced Excel, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Salesforce, Jira, InDesign, Al, WordPress; People management, B2B Sales, Copywriting, Customer Service.